<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kev</title>
    <link>https://kevch.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on kev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 Copyright Kevin Chin (&lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/kevinmkchin&#39; style=&#39;text-decoration: none;&#39;&gt;@kevinmkchin&lt;/a&gt;). All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:35:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevch.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ascent</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/ascent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/ascent/</guid>
      <description>redirecting... </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things I&#39;ve learned about 3D Math and Common sources of confusion</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/3d-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 11:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/3d-math/</guid>
      <description>I am by no means an expert in math, but having worked with linear algebra and math in 3D spaces for years now, I think it could be valuable to share some things that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and some common sources of confusion when it comes to working in 3D spaces. At the very least, I can provide some insight into working with 3D maths as a game or game engine developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Invented Here</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/not-invented-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 06:55:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/not-invented-here/</guid>
      <description>The California Institute of Technology archived a photograph of Richard Feynman&amp;rsquo;s blackboard at the time of his death.
At the top, Feynman wrote: &amp;ldquo;What I cannot create, I do not understand.&amp;rdquo; This is a quote that resonates with me strongly. It&amp;rsquo;s an idea that John Carmack, founder of id Software and pioneer of computer games, seems to agree with.
&amp;ldquo;There are lots of viable paths through engineering. The path I advocate for is &amp;lsquo;knowledge in depth&amp;rsquo; - for knowing things really deeply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Developer Console to your C&#43;&#43; Game in 20 Lines of Code</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/how-to-add-console-to-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 12:01:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/how-to-add-console-to-game/</guid>
      <description>Many computer games have a developer console or in-game console which provide a command-line interface for executing commands, changing game variables, or activating cheats. It&amp;rsquo;s a very useful feature seen in many games like Quake, Skyrim, Minecraft, and Counter-Strike. In this guide, I will explain how to add a complete developer console to your C++ game in 20 lines of code.
The following is an in-game console present in every Source game:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to switch Windows App to Console App</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/switch-windows-app-to-console-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:47:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/switch-windows-app-to-console-app/</guid>
      <description>When making a C++ executable on Windows, you have the option of choosing between a Windows app and a Console app. A Windows app is an app with a GUI Window, and a Console app runs in the terminal (e.g. Windows Command Prompt). By switching over a Windows App to a Console App, you will get a command prompt window accompanying your GUI program Window.
Linker Option Visual Studio or MSVC C++ Compiler Set the /SUBSYSTEM linker option of the MSVC compiler for your project to CONSOLE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Guide to PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/posh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 14:17:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/posh/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find the perfect shell for Windows. There are some decent options out there (e.g. Cmder), but in many ways Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own PowerShell (aka PoSh, PwSh, psh) is the best option for Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s also cross-platform! If you have workflow you are used to with PowerShell, you can have the same workflow regardless of the OS you&amp;rsquo;re on.
PowerShell stands out from other shells available on Windows because it&amp;rsquo;s more than just a command line for interacting with Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Kevin Chin</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/about/</guid>
      <description>Current Software engineer at Unity
Previously Worked on an unannounced multiplayer FPS game at Offworld Industries Contact GitHub - @kevinmkchin
Twitter - @kevinmkchin
LinkedIn - @kevinmkchin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XNGINE</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/xngine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/xngine/</guid>
      <description>GitHub 3D graphics game engine written in C++ with OpenGL. GLEW for OpenGL interface. SDL for window creation and input. Open Asset Importer for importing 3D models.
How to Build and Run Windows Run build-win64-cmake.bat (requires CMake) Run run.bat (with argument &amp;ldquo;vs&amp;rdquo; if you want to launch Visual Studio to debug) Profit Features Deferred rendering Tiled light culling The following image shows a scene with 4000 light sources running at an acceptable 76 frames per second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADK (Ayax Development Kit)</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/adk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/adk/</guid>
      <description>GitHub &amp;ldquo;Hey, good luck on your engine.&amp;rdquo; - Noel Berry Aug 14, 2020 at a bouldering gym Purpose Ayax Development Kit is a collection of tools and resources that one would want in order to create a 2D video game. In essence, ADK is an easy-to-use C++ game engine for building modern 2D games, but it includes several useful game systems such as character controllers, cameras, and common game objects such as trigger boxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Whiplash</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/superwhiplash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/superwhiplash/</guid>
      <description>Steam Store Page I created an online multiplayer vehicular combat game inspired by Twisted Metal called Super Whiplash. This was a significant challenge because the built-in UE4 vehicle controller doesn&amp;rsquo;t work very well in multiplayer. I implemented an entirely new vehicle physics system with framerate independent physics. I networked vehicle physics (e.g. force, traction, etc.) in a way that would work with my system. The result is a bit janky but still more reliable than the built-in UE4 vehicle controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Machina</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/project-machina/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/project-machina/</guid>
      <description>3D game made in Java with OpenGL inspired by 90&amp;rsquo;s FPS games like Doom and Hexen.
[W][A][S][D] to move, [SPACE] to jump, [LMB] to shoot.
Download Project Machina 0.1 Features currently implemented in the source code: Collision through Pixel-perfect Axis-Aligned Bounding Box Chunk-loading (loading revelant chunks of a level instead of the entire level) Random level generation Save and Load level files Scenes and Entities GUI History This game is built off of a heavily modified version of my game engine that I wrote in 2019: Ajax Engine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dream of Flight</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/dream-of-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/dream-of-flight/</guid>
      <description>A 2D platformer game inspired by EXOK&amp;rsquo;s Celeste. Built with C# on the MonoGame Framework.
[A] to move left, [D] to move right, [J] to jump, [K] to toggle flying.
Levels for this game are made using an old level editor I made: Bambuu TileMap Editor
Source Code GitHub Repo
Download Release 1.0 Gameplay Video Screenshots </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>first hello</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/first-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/first-hello/</guid>
      <description>redirecting... </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raycasting Renderer</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/raycasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/raycasting/</guid>
      <description>GitHub This is a demonstration of a video game graphics rendering technique known as Raycasting (find out more about raycasting here: Raycasting Explained). Inspired by John Carmack&amp;rsquo;s implementation of raycasting in Wolfenstein 3D.
The tile map editor that I made to create levels for this the demo became a standalone tile map/level editor which I used for other projects: Bambuu TileMap Editor.
[W][A][S][D] to move.
Download Demo Download Demo gifs </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bambuu Level Editor</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/bambuu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/bambuu/</guid>
      <description>TileMap/Level creator for video games.
Download Release 1.0.0 Features Quickly and easily create tilemaps/levels for platformers, top-down shooters, etc. Use your own custom image files for the tiles. Save and load tilemaps for iterative level design. Up to 3 layers for a single tilemap file. (e.g. one layer for level, one layer for enemies, one layer for items) Up to 48 tiles (will add more later). Fill screen tool. Variable TileMap dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settlers of the Rapture</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/settlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/settlers/</guid>
      <description>Roguelike project that uses Perlin noise to procedurally generate the world.
I gained experience working with the concept of tiles in both 2 and 3 dimensions. This was very beneficial to me in my future projects such as the Bambuu Tilemap Editor, the Raycasting Demonstration, and the Arx Aeternus OpenGL game, all of which use some variation of tilemaps.
Download Demo Download Demo Gif Screenshots </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ajax 3D Engine</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/projects/ajax3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/projects/ajax3d/</guid>
      <description>redirecting... </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
