<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on kev</title>
    <link>https://kevch.in/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on kev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 Copyright Kevin Chin (&lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/kevinmkchin&#39;&gt;@kevinmkchin&lt;/a&gt;). All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 12:01:11 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevch.in/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add a Developer Console to your C&#43;&#43; Game in 20 Lines of Code</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/how-to-add-console-to-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 12:01:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/how-to-add-console-to-game/</guid>
      <description>Many computer games have a developer console or in-game console which provide a command-line interface for executing commands, changing game variables, or activating cheats. It&amp;rsquo;s a very useful feature seen in many games like Quake, Skyrim, Minecraft, and Counter-Strike. In this guide, I will explain how to add a complete developer console to your C++ game in 20 lines of code.
The following is an in-game console present in every Source game:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to switch Windows App to Console App</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/switch-windows-app-to-console-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 10:47:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/switch-windows-app-to-console-app/</guid>
      <description>When making a C++ executable on Windows, you have the option of choosing between a Windows app and a Console app. A Windows app is an app with a GUI Window, and a Console app runs in the terminal (e.g. Windows Command Prompt). By switching over a Windows App to a Console App, you will get a command prompt window accompanying your GUI program Window.
Linker Option Visual Studio or MSVC C++ Compiler Set the /SUBSYSTEM linker option of the MSVC compiler for your project to CONSOLE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Carmack UMKC Commencement Speech</title>
      <link>https://kevch.in/blog/john-carmack-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 10:45:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevch.in/blog/john-carmack-speech/</guid>
      <description>The California Institute of Technology archived a photograph of Richard Feynman&amp;rsquo;s blackboard at the time of his death.
  At the top, Feynman wrote: &amp;ldquo;What I cannot create, I do not understand.&amp;rdquo; This is a quote that resonates with me strongly. It&amp;rsquo;s an idea that John Carmack, founder of id Software and pioneer of computer games, seems to agree with.
  &amp;ldquo;There are lots of viable paths through engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
